{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Undercut is provided on buckets to:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To reduce weight of the buckets",
        "b": "To reduce size of the buckets",
        "c": "To avoid interference of water jet with incoming buckets",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Splitter on buckets is used for:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To reduce impact force on the bucket",
        "b": "To strength the bucket",
        "c": "To help split water jet into and change its direction",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Most widely used turbine for electricity generation:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Pelton",
        "b": "Kalpan",
        "c": "Francis",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Governor in Pelton Turbine is used for:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To improve efficiency",
        "b": "To maintain constant RPM",
        "c": "To provide emergency shutdown",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. A Pelton wheel is to be designed with a wheel pitch dia. of 1 m and jet dia. of 0.1 m. the number of buckets required:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "25",
        "b": "20",
        "c": "15",
        "d": "10"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Which component is not provided to Pelton wheel turbine?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Jet",
        "b": "Penstock",
        "c": "Draft tube",
        "d": "Casing"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. The hydraulic efficiency of Pelton turbine will be maximum when blade velocity is equal to _______",
      "answers": {
        "a": "V/2",
        "b": "V/3",
        "c": "V/4",
        "d": "V/5"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. In Pelton turbine ___________ is defined as ratio between power delivered to runner and power supplied at inlet of turbine.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Mechanical efficiency",
        "b": "Volumetric efficiency",
        "c": "Hydraulic efficiency",
        "d": "Overall efficiency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Among the following which turbine has least efficiency?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Pelton turbine",
        "b": "Kaplan turbine",
        "c": "Francis turbine",
        "d": "Propeller turbine"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. The power supplied at inlet of turbine in S.I units is known as_____________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Shaft power",
        "b": "Runner power",
        "c": "Water power",
        "d": "Total power"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}